There is one food that you must avoid in
order to overcome Alzheimer's. In fact,
I don't think you can actually even
improve Alzheimer's symptoms if you
continue to consume this one food. With
Alzheimer's, we have this fire going on
in the brain. We have inflammation,
amaloid plaquing, neuropiary tangles,
which is basically like this big ball of
fishing line that uh develops um right
after the plaquing. So they both work
together and then the immune reaction to
that creates a tremendous amount of
inflammation and all these neurons start
dying. But out of all the factors that
can influence Alzheimer's, positive or
negative, what you eat is the most
important thing. Here's some information
that you probably have never heard
before. Insulin is neuroprotective. It
actually protects your brain cell. It
actually prevents
this amalloid plaquing from developing
and it also prevents the accumulation of
those tangled type fibers that I just
mentioned. There's even therapies that
certain doctors use called intraasal
insulin sprays where they actually spray
insulin up your sinuses so they go right
into the brain and it's been proven that
it increases memory and the ability to
learn. So one big factor relating to
insulin is that if you're deficient in
insulin uh your risk for getting amaloid
plaquing goes up. What increases
insulin? Carbs. So should we start
eating carbs? Okay. Is that going to
help the situation? No. Because carbs
raise blood sugars
and people with high blood sugar like
diabetics have a much higher risk of
getting Alzheimer's. So, this is
confusing because carbs increase insulin
and that should naturally prevent you
from getting Alzheimer's, but it
actually causes Alzheimer's. This is why
some people coined the term type 3
diabetes is Alzheimer's. Okay, here's
the missing information. When you
increase insulin, you instantly create
resistance. The body starts to protect
you against this excess insulin and it
leads to insulin resistance. Okay? When
you have insulin resistance, you
actually have a deficiency of insulin
inside your cells. So more insulin
creates a deficiency of insulin. Sounds
strange, sounds counterintuitive, but
now you know why. Because the body forms
this protective mechanism, which is
insulin resistance. And as far as how
this relates to Alzheimer's, you have
the bloodb brain barrier, okay, that can
actually be resistant to insulin. Now
even though the brain does make a little
bit of insulin, majority of the brain's
insulin is dependent on what's happening
throughout the body. So just as a
diabetic develops insulin resistance
throughout the body, the brain can also
develop insulin resistance as well,
especially in the bloodb brain barrier.
So insulin resistance is the most
important thing you need to understand.
So many people don't understand this and
they're unknowingly making things worse
by feeding their parents and
grandparents the wrong food because the
number one thing that will increase
insulin is carbs. Okay? I'm not talking
about vegetable carbohydrates. I'm
talking about sugars and I'm talking
about refined grains and I'm talking
about grains as well. Yeah. breads,
pasta, cereal, crackers, biscuits,
waffles, pancakes, muffins, juice,
desserts, all these things will
absolutely positively make things worse.
You can't fix Alzheimer's on top of
these carbs. It's impossible. You must
fix insulin resistance. But carbs aren't
the only thing that creates a spike in
insulin. Okay? And by the way, when you
fix insulin resistance, the neurons
finally get the level of insulin that
they need to help this neurop protection
and decrease the inflammation. Now,
carbs in general, especially in the
refined form and sugars, create a
tremendous amount of inflammation too in
the brain. That's in addition to the
insulin problem. All these carbs also
create a lot of mitochondrial damage,
okay? Which destroy the mitochondria,
which is the energy to the neuron
itself.
and also at the same time creating a lot
of oxidation and free radical damage and
a lowered ability to deal with that
because consuming a lot of sugars and
refined carbs decrease your
antioxidants. So we have all this
inflammation without any ability to
counter the inflammation. So, what is
the most important thing you can do if
you have a loved one that has
Alzheimer's or you are starting to
develop symptoms for Alzheimer's is to
understand this mechanism and fix
insulin resistance. And there are
several ways to do it. Okay. Number one,
you must lower your carbs so you can
start shifting your your body running on
ketones, which is a preferred, better,
more efficient fuel to the brain cells.
So, if you get a ketone meter, you want
to make sure you're in ketosis. I'm
talking about.5 to 3 mill moles. That
would be the level that you want to
shoot for. Now, you can also increase
those ketones by doing some other cool
things like adding exercise and adding
fasting, which I think you should do as
well. But the point is, if there's
damage in the brain from this insulin
problem and this glucose problem, thank
goodness there's another pathway you can
actually start feeding the brain cells.
So any patient who has Alzheimer's must
be feeding their brain cells ketones if
they want any chance of turning things
around. Okay, so that's number one,
getting on the ketogenic diet. The next
thing you need to know about insulin
resistance to be able to fix it is that
the frequency of meals, okay, the more
times you eat and snack, the more you're
going to raise insulin. Okay, so you
also must do intermittent fasting. And
if you have signs of Alzheimer's, okay,
or you're at risk, you really need to be
on what's called OMAD, which is one meal
a day. That meal needs to be healthy and
it needs to be big enough and providing
you with all the nutrition.
But allowing your body to fast for 23
hours is super super important because
you're going to keep your insulin low.
You're going to actually start to allow
the neurons to be fed with insulin.
You're going to turn around insulin
resistance so much faster. So the worse
someone has Alzheimer's, the less
frequent they should eat. And you would
see a dramatic improvement if you did
this. So, one meal a day and make sure
that meal is the ketogenic diet. Well,
I'm 57 years old. I'm 6'2. I weigh 185
lbs and I can easily run my body on one
meal a day. Okay, I have more calories,
but my body does very, very, very well
on that. So, anyone that is over the age
of 50 really should be considering uh
one meal a day simply because we don't
need so many calories, especially if
you're not doing hardcore workouts. And
if you talk about Alzheimer's patients,
which are not typically active or
they're in a home or assisted living, I
mean, they're not burning off these
calories. To feed them more than one
meal a day is completely unnecessary.
And unfortunately, they're usually
getting three meals a day plus snacks.
completely way too much food because
anytime you have insulin resistance,
you're going to be craving carbs and
you're going to be hungry all the time.
But as soon as you do one meal a day,
you convert the body over to ketones and
the hunger goes away and the cravings go
away and it makes it really easy to do.
And the fourth thing is to make sure
that meal is really healthy and
nutrient-dense. The next thing you need
to know, do whatever you can to lower
stress. Stress activates cortisol.
Another name for cortisol is
glucocorticoids, which has to do with
glucose. So in other words, anytime you
increase cortisol, you increase glucose
and not because you're eating sugar,
just because your body's in a stress
state, that can create insulin
resistance, that can create even
diabetes. So people that go through
stress chronically or um they're taking
predinazone or some type of synthetic
cortisone for pain, wow, it's like
eating sugar. There's a lot of things
you can do. I just want you to get the
concept. You want to lower the stress.
The points I just mentioned are like a
requirement from any plan if you're
trying to turn this uh Alzheimer's
around. And the next most important
video to watch would be that video I did
on what to eat. Okay? What would that
one meal a day consist of to be healthy?
And I put that video up right here.
Check it out.